<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>bookstudy - Category - Chess Study</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/categories/bookstudy/</link><description>bookstudy - Category - Chess Study</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:04:49 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://yanghu.github.io/chess/categories/bookstudy/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. First Principles: Endings, Middle-game and Openings</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/chess-fundamentals/first-principles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 16:16:44 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/chess-fundamentals/first-principles/</guid><description><![CDATA[Single pawn  The King should be in front of his Pawn, with at least one intervening square. Advance the King as far as possible with the safety of the pawn, and never to advance the Pawn until it is essential to its own safety.  Other Pawn Endings Don&#39;t push pawns prematurely don&rsquo;t push the pawn prematurely, which may send it to the opponent&rsquo;s King, and you can&rsquo;t protect it.]]></description></item><item><title>Imbalances and Bishop vs Knight</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/amateurs-mind/imbalances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 22:17:41 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/amateurs-mind/imbalances/</guid><description>Imbalances: the static and dynamic differences.
List of imbalances Minor pieces: the interplay between Bishops and Knights Pawn structure: doubled/isolated/backward/passed pawns, islands. Space Material Files and squares: files, ranks and diagonals act as pathway, while squares act as homes. Development: this is a temporary balance. Initiative: also temporary. Don&amp;#39;t look at individual moves! Try to understand the position, before starting calculation on individual moves. Bishop vs Knights It&amp;rsquo;s the most important imbalance of the game.</description></item><item><title>The Center, Territory and Space</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/amateurs-mind/center-and-space/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 23:18:05 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/amateurs-mind/center-and-space/</guid><description>Amateurs often have no clue of how to use center/space advantage, instead keen on forcing continuations, and unjustified attacks.
Rules of center Rule 1. Full pawn center gives control and space. A full pawn center gives its owner territory and control over key central squares.
Rule 2. Owning a center is responsibility. Owning a full pawn center is a responsibility. You must make it indestructible, and you will cramp your opponent.</description></item><item><title>Pawn Structure</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/amateurs-mind/pawns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:04:49 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/amateurs-mind/pawns/</guid><description>Knowning which pawn structure is &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; is not enough: one need to know how to attack them, or making use of the weaknesses.
In general, the formular to attack weak pawns(isolated, backward) is to control the square in front of the pawn so it can&amp;rsquo;t advance. (the squares are usually weak since no pawn can defend it). Then pile up on the weakness.
Every structure has its pros and cons.</description></item><item><title>4. General Theory</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/chess-fundamentals/general-theory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 22:12:23 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/chess-fundamentals/general-theory/</guid><description>Lichess study of this chapter Embedded chessboard from lichess.org
The initiative White has the move, which means initiative. He tries to first control the center, or obtain some positional advantage, so it&amp;rsquo;s possible for him to keep on harrassing the enemy.
He only relinquishes the initiative when he gets for some material advantage in return.
Diract attack en masse Attack en masse Attacks must be carried on with sufficient force to gurantee its success.</description></item><item><title>5. End Game Strategy</title><link>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/chess-fundamentals/end-game-strategy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 22:26:15 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>http://yanghu.github.io/chess/posts/chess-fundamentals/end-game-strategy/</guid><description>Lichess study of this chapter Embedded chessboard from lichess.org
The sudden attack from a different side Similar to general theory, the idea is to first attacking on one side, then, with greater mobility of the pieces, quickly transfer attack to the other side and break through, before the opponent can respond.
Rooks and pawns endings The rooks and pawns endings are difficult. Usually, the idea is to forcing opponent to defend a weak point, removing their mobility, and use our own greater mobility to switch side and attack.</description></item></channel></rss>